Hello, everyone. I'm here to talk about
the semantic SEO in a simplified way.
The plan for the presentation
is really simple.
We're gonna talk about
what it is, why it works,
how you can implement it, and how
we can use AI to actually process,
these things. So first,
what is semantic SEO?
The best way to explain it is you can
think of it as organizing all of the
information on your website.
A much simpler way to think
about it is it is a more
detailed on-page optimization.
In on-page we have simple things
like title, alt text, URLs, headings,
that's it. In semantics we
have a ton of different things
and I'll try to not look like this
guy, but in five minutes I might.
So what are these things
that I'm talking about?
Imagine that this is a passage of text.
On the top we have a heading and
that's just a regular paragraph.
In semantics, we care very
deeply what is the first
sentence, what are the words there, what
exactly what it contains and in which
order these words are appearing.
Also, if we have a really,
let's say, long text,
where do we break it into
different paragraphs?
Since we have different paragraphs, how do
we end the first paragraph and start the
next one? And then also, let's say the
information that goes inside the first
paragraph, someone was
bringing up the triples.
This is really important to place in the
correct order to address the heading that
it is above. So let's say right
here we have the first paragraph,
then we have the second one.
The way we start with second one and
how we address the heading is a really
important aspect for us. So you can
already understand words that we use,
where they go, in which
order is important.
Once we process a single
passage like this,
then we wanna apply that
to all of other passages.
You can see that we're building things
block by block and ultimately sentence by
sentence. Of course, we use a
hierarchy for all the headings as in,
let's say, H2 would be the main aspect,
H3 would be sub aspects or let's say a sub
topic for that. This is applied
throughout the entire article.
We always have a different
type of, let's say, of course,
it's just an example. Sometimes
we can go down to H5, H6,
sometimes we can have most H2 tags.
There's always variations.
Approximately, this is how
the article will look like.
And then we always have two parts.
What this is what we call the macro
context and the micro context or the main
part and the supplementary part.
The thing that is important to understand
about this is the main part is directly
addressing the query. This is where we
need to meet all of the needs of the user.
So if they need if they
have informational needs,
we try to give them all the answers.
If they need some kind of navigational
visual or a functional thing where they
need to book or order something, we
give that in the main upper part.
The bottom part, the supplementary part
is used for linking and just deepening,
the context. In this, type of layout,
we have a single article that is now
completed. We apply the same principle
to all of the articles on our website.
As we do that, there is a clear pattern.
We can see that there's a
hierarchy between these articles.
Some are more important and have, let's
say, a different reason why we use them.
Now to just simplify this visualization,
we're gonna turn them into these simple
circles. And this is what we
call root, seed, and node.
Do not, let's say, get confused by this.
Just think of them as three types of
articles and they have different levels of
importance. Then we build out different
connections based on these principles.
A more, let's say, connected
representation would look something like
this or like this. As you can
see over here, we have a central,
root article, then we have multiple seeds.
These are the orange circles
and then the blue ones.
These are the nodes, the
small, tiny articles.
This can represent